Cardinal: UNDER THE ALL-POWERFUL
ADMINISTRATOR’S RULE,
THIS WORLD ENTERED
A LONG PERIOD OF PEACE,
AND THE PEOPLE BECAME APATHETIC.
70 YEARS HAD PASSED SINCE
QUINELLA BECAME ADMINISTRATOR.
THEN, ONE DAY,
SHE REALIZED
SHE’D UNDERGONE A CHANGE.
SHE USED HER CONTROL COMMAND
TO EXAMINE HER FLUCTLIGHT
AND DISCOVERED
IT HAD REACHED ITS CAPACITY
TO RETAIN HER MEMORIES.
SHE REFUSED TO ACCEPT IT,
SO SHE CAME UP WITH
ANOTHER MONSTROUS SOLUTION.
Administrator: WELCOME, CHILD.
PLEASE, COME CLOSER.
Girl: YES, MA’AM.
Administrator: IF I CAN
OVERWRITE HER FLUCTLIGHT
WITH A COPY OF THE THOUGHTS
AND MEMORIES FROM MY OWN,
I WILL NEVER LOSE THEM.
CLOSE YOUR EYES.
( girl whimpers )
Cardinal: IT WAS
A DIABOLICAL CEREMONY...
A FUSING OF SOUL AND MEMORY
WHICH SHE CALLED
THE SYNTHESIS RITUAL.
WITH IT, SHE COULD SEIZE CONTROL
OF ANOTHER HUMAN’S FLUCTLIGHT.
AND HERE WAS
WHERE ADMINISTRATOR,
OR QUINELLA,
MADE A CRITICAL MISTAKE.
Kirito: WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
Cardinal: IT DIDN’T OCCUR TO HER
THAT, DURING THE PROCESS
OF TAKING OVER THE YOUNG GIRL
AND DELETING HER OLD SELF,
THERE WOULD BE A SPLIT SECOND
WHERE TWO GODS WITH EQUAL POWER
EXISTED AT THE SAME TIME.
KIRITO, YOU ARE FAMILIAR
WITH MY ORIGINAL VERSION,
ARE YOU NOT?
WHAT IS THE MAIN FEATURE
OF THE CARDINAL SYSTEM?
Kirito: OH, UM...
IT’S SUPPOSED
TO OPERATE AUTOMATICALLY
FOR LONG PERIODS OF TIME.
IT DOESN’T NEED HUMANS TO RUN.
Cardinal: THAT IS CORRECT,
AND, TO FACILITATE IT,
THE CARDINAL SYSTEM
HAS TWO CORE PROGRAMS,
A MAIN PROCESS AND A SUBPROCESS.
THE MAIN PROCESS PERFORMS
BALANCE CONTROLS ON THE SYSTEM.
Kirito: WHILE THE SUBPROCESS
RUNS ERROR CHECKS ON THE MAIN.
Cardinal: PRECISELY.
WHEN SHE BECAME ADMINISTRATOR,
THE PRESERVATION OF ORDER
WASN’T THE ONLY THING QUINELLA
ETCHED ONTO HER FLUCTLIGHT.
IN THE RECESSES OF HER SOUL,
I STILL FUNCTIONED
AS THE SUBPROCESS TO HER MAIN,
AND I WAS OBLIGATED
TO CORRECT HER ERRORS.
( Kirito gasps )
Cardinal: FOR 70 LONG YEARS,
I WAITED FOR MY OPPORTUNITY...
AND FINALLY IT HAD ARRIVED!
♪
♪ SHINY SWORD, MY DIAMOND ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ IT’S TIME ♪
♪
Administrator: IT WORKED.
THIS LITTLE GIRL’S FLUCTLIGHT
IS MINE NOW.
- Cardinal: SYSTEM CALL.
- ( Administrator gasps )
Cardinal:
GENERATE LUMINOUS ELEMENT.
LIGHTNING SHAPE. DISCHARGE!
Administrator: WHAT?
Cardinal: SYSTEM CALL!
GENERATE LUMINOUS ELEMENT!
Administrator: SYSTEM CALL!
GENERATE UMBRA ELEMENT.
BALL SHAPE!
Both: DISCHARGE!
Administrator: SYSTEM CALL!
REDEFINE OBJECT!
SWORD CLASS!
Cardinal: SYSTEM CALL.
REDEFINE OBJECT!
ROD CLASS!
Administrator: SYSTEM CALL!
CHANGE FIELD ATTRIBUTE!
Cardinal: NO!
SHE MADE THIS AREA OFF-LIMITS
FOR SYSTEM COMMANDS.
- ( Administrator grunts )
- ( Cardinal grunts )
I CAN’T DEFEAT HER
IN THIS BODY.
( gasps )
( staff rings clinking )
( Administrator gasps )
Cardinal: SYSTEM CALL!
GENERATE AERIAL ELEMENT!
STREAM SHAPE!
( narrating ) THERE ARE ONLY
TWO LOCATIONS IN THIS WORLD
WHICH ADMINISTRATOR
HAS NO CONTROL OVER.
ONE IS THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE END MOUNTAINS.
THE OTHER IS...
SYSTEM CALL!
GENERATE BLIZZARD GATE.
ZERO ONE!
( narrating )
...THE GREAT LIBRARY!
IN AN INSTANT,
THIS SPACE WAS COMPLETELY
ISOLATED FROM THE OUTSIDE.
FOR THE PAST 200 YEARS,
I’VE BEEN WATCHING AND PLOTTING.
I WAITED FOR THE PERFECT MOMENT
WHEN I COULD CATCH HER
OFF GUARD, THEN AMBUSH HER.
SHE KNEW WHAT I WAS UP TO
AND WAS CONSTANTLY ON GUARD,
SO SHE CREATED POWERFUL AND
LOYAL SERVANTS FOR PROTECTION.
Administrator:
THROUGH THE SYNTHESIS RITUAL,
THIS MAN WILL BE REBORN
AS A WARRIOR DEVOTED ONLY TO ME,
MY INTEGRITY KNIGHT!
( chorus vocalizing )
Cardinal: THE FIRST ONE SHE
TURNED INTO AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT
WAS AN EXCEPTIONAL SWORDSMAN
WHO HATED
THE RULE OF THE CHURCH.
SEEKING REFUGE FROM IT,
HE AND HIS COMPANIONS FOUNDED
A VILLAGE IN THE OUTER REGIONS.
THE NAME OF THIS KNIGHT
WAS BERCOULI SYNTHESIS ONE.
ONE-ON-ONE, ADMINISTRATOR AND I
ARE EQUALLY MATCHED.
AT LEAST, WE WERE.
HER KNIGHTS
ARE FAST AND POWERFUL.
THEY MADE THE PROSPECT
OF AMBUSHING HER IMPOSSIBLE,
SO, AT THE RISK
OF BEING SPOTTED,
I SOUGHT OUT MY OWN ALLIES.
I OPENED DOORWAYS
FAR FROM THE CATHEDRAL,
THEN CAST
SENSORY SHARING SPELLS
UPON BIRDS AND INSECTS
AND SENT THEM OUT
TO LEAD POTENTIAL ALLIES
BACK HERE TO ME.
( chuckles )
Kirito: UH...
HUH? ( gasps )
Cardinal: LOOK HERE.
MEET CHARLOTTE.
SHE SPOTTED
YOU AND EUGEO IN RULID
AND HAS BEEN
TAGGING ALONG WITH YOU
EVER SINCE YOU LEFT THAT PLACE.
SOMETIMES SHE DID MORE
THAN JUST TAG ALONG.
( Kirito gasps )
SHE WAS THE ONE GUIDING ME
WHEN WE WERE RUNNING
FROM THAT KNIGHT.
HUH! SNEAKY.
SO BACK WHEN MY ZEPHILIAS
GOT CHOPPED UP,
WAS THAT YOU
GIVING ME THE PEP TALK?
UH...
Cardinal: SHE’S A SHY ONE.
OF ALL MY OBSERVATION UNITS,
CHARLOTTE HAS BEEN OUT SEARCHING
LONGER THAN THE OTHERS.
AT LAST, SHE CAN REST NOW.
HER MISSION’S COME TO AN END.
WHEN I ENLISTED HER,
I FROZE THE NATURAL DEGRADATION
OF HER LIFE.
THAT WAS OVER 200 YEARS AGO.
( Kirito sighs )
THANKS, CHARLOTTE.
SO, FOR 200 YEARS,
YOU HAD CRITTERS LIKE HER OUT
IN THE WORLD LOOKING FOR HELP,
AND YOU’VE BEEN STUCK
IN HERE THE WHOLE TIME?
Cardinal: INDEED,
AND, AS I SAT HERE
OBSERVING THE WORLD
THROUGH THEIR EYES,
A QUESTION KEPT REPEATING.
WHY WOULD THE GODS
OF THE OUTSIDE
ABANDON A WORLD THEY CREATED
TO SUFFER UNDER THE TYRANNY
OF ADMINISTRATOR, A FALSE GOD?
AS I PONDERED THIS AND REFERRED
TO THE CARDINAL SYSTEM’S
BUILT-IN DATABASE OVER AND OVER,
I EVENTUALLY ARRIVED
AT A CONCLUSION.
RATH MAY BE THE GOD HERE,
BUT IT DOESN’T WANT THE PEOPLE
TO LEAD HAPPY LIVES AT ALL.
IT WANTS THE OPPOSITE.
THIS IS A TEST.
RATH CREATED THE UNDERWORLD
SO THEY CAN OBSERVE
HOW ITS PEOPLE REACT
TO STRESS PARAMETERS
PUT UPON THEM.
DAY BY DAY, THEY INCREASE.
EVENTUALLY ALL THOSE STRESSORS
WILL REACH THEIR LIMIT,
AND THE FINAL PHASE OF THE TEST
WILL BE AT HAND.
Kirito: THEN WHAT HAPPENS?
Cardinal: WHAT THESE PEOPLE
FEAR THE MOST,
AN INVASION
FROM OUTSIDE THIS REALM.
Kirito: THE DARK TERRITORY.
Cardinal: CORRECT. THE WORLD
OF DARKNESS WAS CREATED
TO SUBJECT THE UNDERWORLDIANS
TO THE ULTIMATE AGONY.
THE MONSTERS THERE HAVE
FLUCTLIGHTS, JUST LIKE HUMANS.
THE DIFFERENCE IS,
THEIR PRIME DIRECTIVE
IS TO PLUNDER AND SLAUGHTER.
THEY’RE EAGER FOR THE DAY
WHEN THEY CAN BREACH
THE LAND OF THE IUMS,
AS THEY CALL YOU,
AND WREAK HAVOC.
THAT DAY IS COMING.
Kirito: AND ADMINISTRATOR,
DOES SHE KNOW THEY’RE COMING?
Cardinal: YES,
BUT SHE UNDERESTIMATES THEM.
SHE THINKS SHE
AND HER INTEGRITY KNIGHTS
ARE STRONG ENOUGH TO REPEL THEM.
SHE EVEN HAD
ALL FOUR GUARDIAN DRAGONS SLAIN,
NORTH, SOUTH, EAST, AND WEST.
AS ALLIES,
THEY WOULD HAVE BEEN VALUABLE,
BUT SHE COULD NOT CONTROL THEM.
PITY, SHE CANNOT WIN NOW,
FOR THE FORCES OF DARKNESS
ARE TOO MANY,
AND HER NUMBERS ARE TOO FEW.
Kirito: HANG ON. IF THAT’S TRUE,
THEN WHY BOTHER TAKIN’ HER DOWN?
’CAUSE IT SOUNDS LIKE
THE FATE OF THIS WORLD’S SEALED
WHETHER YOU DO OR DON’T.
Cardinal: YOU ARE CORRECT.
( Kirito gasps )
Cardinal: NO MATTER WHAT I DO,
THE DARK TERRITORY
WILL INVADE THE HUMAN REALM,
AND THERE IS NO STOPPING IT.
Kirito: SO, LIKE,
ONCE YOU STOP ADMINISTRATOR,
YOUR JOB HERE’S DONE,
AND WHATEVER ELSE HAPPENS
HAPPENS.
YOU DON’T CARE, DO YOU?
Cardinal: PERHAPS I DON’T.
HOWEVER...
RATH ENGINEERED
THE BLOODSHED THAT IS TO COME.
I CANNOT ACCEPT
A GOD WHO DOES THAT.
ONCE I LEARNED THE STRESS TEST
WAS UNAVOIDABLE, I DECIDED.
THE HUMAN REALM
AND THE DARK TERRITORY
MUST BE RETURNED TO NOTHINGNESS.
Kirito: HOLD UP. DECIDED?
Cardinal: THAT IS WHAT I SAID.
WHEN I REGAIN CONTROL,
I WILL ACCESS THE FLUCTLIGHTS
STORED IN THE LIGHTCUBE CLUSTER.
THEN I WILL DELETE
EVERY RESIDENT
OF THE REALMS
OF HUMANITY AND DARKNESS.
- ( Kirito shudders )
- Cardinal: THAT SAID,
IF YOU DECIDE TO HELP ME
AND I ELIMINATE ADMINISTRATOR,
I WILL HAVE FULL ACCESS
TO ALL OF MY AUTHORITY.
THEN, BEFORE I
EXTINGUISH THIS WORLD,
I CAN GRANT YOU ONE WISH,
TO A CERTAIN DEGREE, ANYWAY.
IF YOU SINGLE OUT
THOSE YOU WOULD LIKE TO SAVE,
I WILL REFRAIN
FROM DELETING THEIR FLUCTLIGHTS.
- INSTEAD, I WILL ARCHIVE THEM.
- ( Kirito gasps )
Cardinal: AFTER YOU ESCAPE
TO THE REAL WORLD,
YOU CAN SAVE THEIR LIGHTCUBES.
I SHOULD BE ABLE
TO SET ASIDE TEN OR SO.
( Kirito gasps )
I GOTTA PICK?
WAIT A SEC.
SOMETHING DOESN’T ADD UP HERE.
YOU SAID YOUR SOUL’S
A COPY OF HERS.
THAT MEANS
YOU GOT THE SELFISH PART
OF THE NOBILITY IN YOU, TOO,
THE DRIVE TO PUT YOUR WANTS
AND NEEDS ABOVE EVERYONE ELSE’S.
SO WHY’D YOU WAIT HERE ALL
BY YOURSELF AND FOR 200 YEARS?
YOU COULD HAVE FOUND A PLACE
FAR AWAY FROM ADMINISTRATOR
AND HAD SOME KINDA LIFE.
( Cardinal sighs )
THE CARDINAL SUBPROCESS
WAS BURNED INTO ME.
THAT MEANS MY CORE DESIRES
AMOUNT TO ONLY ONE THING,
TO ELIMINATE ADMINISTRATOR AND
RESTORE NORMAL FUNCTION HERE.
TO ME, THERE IS NO WAY TO HAVE
A PROPERLY FUNCTIONING WORLD,
UNLESS THE CORRUPTING ELEMENT
IS DEALT WITH
AND THE SLATE WIPED CLEAN.
ACTUALLY, ON SECOND THOUGHT...
( Kirito sighs )
Cardinal: PERHAPS YOU’RE RIGHT.
I DO HARBOR ONE DESIRE,
SOMETHING I WAS
DESPERATE TO EXPERIENCE
JUST ONCE
FOR THE LAST 200 YEARS.
KIRITO,
WOULD YOU STAND UP, PLEASE?
Kirito: UH...
( Cardinal groans )
Cardinal: THIS SHOULD DO.
ALL RIGHT, PLEASE STEP FORWARD.
- COME CLOSER.
- Kirito: WHY?
Cardinal: DON’T ARGUE WITH ME!
RAISE YOUR ARMS, PLEASE.
Kirito: LIKE THIS?
Cardinal: IN FRONT OF YOU,
AND MAKE A CIRCLE WITH THEM.
Kirito: UH...
Cardinal: HONESTLY,
HOW DENSE ARE YOU?
SO THIS IS IT.
NOW I SEE.
THIS IS
WHAT IT MEANS TO BE HUMAN.
( Kirito grunts )
( Cardinal gasps )
TO BE HELD,
IT’S SO WARM AND COMFORTING.
AFTER 200 YEARS,
THIS MAKES THE WAIT WORTH IT.
TO THINK SOMETHING SO SIMPLE
COULD BE SO SATISFYING.
THE WAIT
WAS MORE THAN WORTH IT.
- ( robe flaps )
- ( Kirito gasps )
Cardinal: HMM?
WELL? HOW LONG ARE YOU PLANNING
TO STAND THERE LIKE THAT?
Kirito: SORRY. JUST BEIN’ HUMAN!
Cardinal: SO THEN,
WHAT’S YOUR DECISION?
Kirito: UH...
Cardinal: WILL YOU HELP ME
STOP ADMINISTRATOR OR NOT?
( Kirito sighs )
YEAH, OKAY.
I’LL HELP YOU WITH THIS PLAN
OF YOURS, SORT OF.
Cardinal: HUH?
Kirito: LOOK, I GET WHERE
YOU’RE COMING FROM AND ALL,
BUT I’M NOT GONNA GIVE UP
ON THIS WORLD,
AND I WON’T GIVE UP
ON ITS PEOPLE.
I’LL HELP YOU, BUT I’LL STILL
TRY AND FIND A WAY TO SAVE ’EM.
Cardinal: HONESTLY,
YOUR OPTIMISM IS ABSURD.
Kirito: MAYBE SO,
BUT IF EVERYTHING GETS DELETED,
SO DO YOU.
( Cardinal gasps )
Kirito: IF I CAN’T
FIGURE THIS OUT, YOU CAN BET
YOU’LL BE ONE OF THE TEN PEOPLE
I’M GONNA WANT SAVED.
( Cardinal sighs )
COULD YOU BE ANY MORE FOOLISH?
HOW DO YOU EXPECT ME
TO EXTINGUISH THIS WORLD
IF I AM NOT PRESENT
TO PERFORM THE TASK?
Kirito: DON’T KNOW.
HEY, I’LL DO WHATEVER YOU SAY,
BUT I’M GONNA TRY TO COME UP
WITH A BETTER SOLUTION
ALL THE SAME.
( Cardinal groans )
SOMEDAY, YOU, TOO, WILL KNOW
THE BITTERNESS OF RESIGNATION.
IT IS NOT THE SAME
AS TRYING AND FAILING.
IT IS BEING FORCED
TO ADMIT FAILURE,
REGARDLESS OF HOW HARD YOU TRY.
( footsteps approaching )
( Eugeo sighs )
Kirito: THERE YOU ARE!
WE THOUGHT
YOU WERE STILL IN THE BATH.
Eugeo: I’M SORRY.
I GUESS I LOST TRACK OF TIME.
Kirito: SO, UH,
CARDINAL AND I WERE TALKIN’.
SHE USED TO BE THE--
THE PONTIFEX HERE
’TIL ADMINISTRATOR KICKED
HER OUT AND TOOK OVER HER JOB.
Eugeo: YOU WERE A PONTIFEX?
Kirito: DON’T WORRY.
SHE’S ON OUR SIDE.
SHE’S GONNA HELP US FIGHT
THE INTEGRITY KNIGHTS.
- Eugeo: Y-YOU WILL?
- Kirito: YEAH.
SHE WANTS TO GET HER TITLE
AS PONTIFEX BACK,
BUT TO DO THAT,
SHE’S GONNA HAVE TO TAKE DOWN
ADMINISTRATOR FIRST,
SO, LIKE, SHE SORT OF
SUGGESTED WE JOIN FORCES.
Cardinal: MM-HMM.
Eugeo: THERE’S THIS GIRL,
AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT
CALLED ALICE SYNTHESIS THIRTY.
I THINK SHE’S THE SAME PERSON
AS AN ALICE ZUBERG FROM RULID.
DO YOU KNOW IF SHE IS?
Cardinal: I’M SORRY,
BUT THE INFORMATION
I’M ABLE TO ACCESS HERE
IS EXTREMELY LIMITED.
I KNOW INTEGRITY KNIGHT ALICE
WAS BORN, BUT NO OTHER DETAILS.
HOWEVER, I CAN TELL YOU HOW
TO UNDO THE SYNTHESIS RITUAL,
THE SACRED ART
THAT CREATES INTEGRITY KNIGHTS.
( Eugeo gasps )
AND HOW DO I DO THAT?
Cardinal: SIMPLY REMOVE
THE PIETY MODULE.
ALL THE KNIGHTS HAVE ONE
IN THEIR FOREHEAD.
IT LOOKS LIKE
A TRIANGULAR PRISM.
( Eugeo gasps ) WE SAW ONE.
Cardinal: ONCE THE PIETY MODULE
IS INSERTED,
IT EFFECTIVELY BLOCKS
THE LINKS TO MEMORIES.
WITH THAT, THE PROSPECTIVE
KNIGHT’S PAST IS SEALED AWAY--
THE RESULT, A KNIGHT
WHO IS LOYAL TO THE CHURCH
AND TO THEIR CREATOR,
THE PONTIFEX.
Kirito: WE ALMOST BROKE
THE SPELL ON ONE OF ’EM.
WE REMINDED HIM
OF WHO HE USED TO BE,
AND THE CRYSTAL POPPED OUT.
Cardinal: THAT IS NOT ENOUGH
TO FREE A KNIGHT.
ANOTHER ELEMENT IS REQUIRED
IN ORDER TO BREAK THE SPELL.
Eugeo: AND? WHAT WOULD THAT BE?
Cardinal: THE THING
THAT ONCE EXISTED
IN THE PLACE
WHERE THE MODULE WAS INSERTED,
OR, MORE SPECIFICALLY,
A MEMORY FRAGMENT,
ONE THE INTEGRITY KNIGHT
TREASURES THE MOST.
ADMINISTRATOR IS
A CAUTIOUS WOMAN.
I DON’T DOUBT SHE KEEPS
ALL THE MEMORY FRAGMENTS
CLOSE AT HAND.
IF ANYWHERE,
THEY’D BE IN HER CHAMBER,
LOCATED ON THE TOP FLOOR
OF THE CENTRAL CATHEDRAL.
Kirito: OKAY,
SO TO TURN THE KNIGHTS
BACK TO THE WAY THEY WERE,
WE NEED TO GET OUR HANDS
ON THEIR MEMORY FRAGMENTS.
BUT I DOUBT
THE INTEGRITY KNIGHTS
ARE JUST GONNA LET US
WALK UP TO ADMINISTRATOR’S ROOM.
I BET WE’RE GONNA HAVE
TO FIGHT EVERY ONE OF ’EM
ALL THE WAY
TO THE TOP OF THE CATHEDRAL.
Cardinal: DON’T BE NAIVE.
AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT
DOES NOT STOP
UNTIL EITHER YOU
OR THEY ARE DEAD.
I CAN HELP YOU GET EQUIPMENT
THAT IS EQUAL TO THEIRS,
BUT THAT IS
ALL THE ASSISTANCE I CAN OFFER.
THE REST WILL BE
UP TO YOUR SKILLS
AND WHETHER YOU HAVE
THE STAMINA TO ENDURE.
Eugeo: IF ALICE SHOWS UP
AND I HAVE TO FIGHT HER,
I-I DON’T WANT TO HURT HER.
I CAN’T.
I JUST WANT TO TAKE HER
BACK TO OUR VILLAGE.
Cardinal: I KNOW. I UNDERSTAND.
YOUR INTENTION IS HONORABLE,
AND I HAVE AN IDEA THAT SHOULD
SATISFY YOU, SO DON’T FRET.
WHEN YOU COME ACROSS
ALICE THE KNIGHT,
YOU’LL BE ARMED WITH SOMETHING
THAT WON’T KILL HER.
I MADE THEM SPECIAL.
Kirito: DAGGERS?
Cardinal: OBVIOUSLY.
WHOEVER THEY PIERCE
WILL BE INSTANTLY LINKED TO ME
IN THIS LIBRARY
BY AN UNBREAKABLE CONNECTION.
THE PERSON
WILL THEN BE SUSCEPTIBLE
TO WHATEVER SACRED ART I CAST.
TAKE THEM. ALL YOU HAVE TO DO
IS PIERCE HER FLESH
WITH JUST ONE
OF THOSE DAGGERS.
IN THAT INSTANT,
I WILL USE MY SACRED ARTS
TO PUT HER INTO A DEEP SLEEP.
SHE WILL STAY THAT WAY UNTIL YOU
HAVE HER MEMORY FRAGMENT
AND ARE READY
TO REMOVE THE SYNTHESIS.
Eugeo: ALL RIGHT, THEN.
IF I CAN’T MANAGE
TO TALK SENSE INTO HER,
I WILL USE YOUR DAGGERS.
Cardinal: ACTUALLY, ONE OF THOSE
IS INTENDED FOR ADMINISTRATOR.
THE OTHER ONE
IS SUPPOSED TO BE A SPARE.
EITHER WAY, WHO GETS STABBED
WITH WHICH IS UP TO YOU NOW.
Kirito: DAMN, TALK ABOUT
PUTTIN’ ON THE PRESSURE.
- WAIT. WE STILL NEED GEAR.
- Cardinal: HMM?
Kirito: YOU SAID
YOU’D HELP US GET STUFF
THAT’S EQUAL
TO WHAT THE KNIGHTS HAVE.
Cardinal: YOU AND EUGEO HAVE
POWERFUL SWORDS OF YOUR OWN,
DO YOU NOT?
THOSE SHOULD BE MORE THAN EQUAL
TO WHAT ANY KNIGHT HAS.
Eugeo: DOES THAT MEAN
WHAT I THINK IT DOES?
CAN YOU GET OUR SWORDS BACK?
Cardinal: OF COURSE.
THERE IS AN ARMORY
ON THE THIRD FLOOR
OF THE CATHEDRAL.
THAT IS MOST LIKELY
WHERE THEY ARE BEING KEPT.
Kirito: BY THE WAY,
HOW FAR UP DO WE HAVE TO GO
TO GET TO ADMINISTRATOR’S ROOM?
Cardinal: EACH YEAR,
THE CENTRAL CATHEDRAL
GROWS TALLER THAN THE LAST,
SO HER CHAMBER SHOULD BE
ON THE 100th FLOOR BY NOW.
( Kirito groans )
Cardinal: UNFORTUNATELY...
THERE IS ONE MORE THING
YOU NEED TO DO.
Kirito: AH. YOU DON’T SAY.
Cardinal:
YOUR SWORDS ARE POWERFUL.
THAT MUCH IS TRUE,
BUT THEY’RE NOT ENOUGH TO BRING
DOWN THE INTEGRITY KNIGHTS.
THEY KNOW A TECHNIQUE
WHICH ALLOWS THEM
TO AMPLIFY
THEIR WEAPONS’S ABILITIES
MANY TIMES
OVER WHAT IS NORMAL.
Eugeo: RIGHT. I BELIEVE IT’S
CALLED PERFECT WEAPON CONTROL.
Cardinal: ONCE THEY
ACTIVATE THE SPELL,
DIVINE WEAPONS
TAKE ON THE PROPERTIES
OF THE THING
THE WEAPON ONCE WAS.
IN OTHER WORDS, PERFECT CONTROL
RELEASES THE WEAPON’S MEMORY.
AS A RESULT,
IT CAN UNLEASH POTENT ATTACKS
THAT ARE FAR BEYOND NORMAL.
I WILL ARM YOU BOTH
WITH THAT POWER.
CLOSE YOUR EYES,
AND THINK OF YOUR SWORD.
♪
( wood creaking )
( crystal clinking )
ALL RIGHT. IT IS DONE.
( staff rings clinking )
( both grunt )
Cardinal: HERE.
Kirito: UH...
Cardinal: COMMIT
ALL THE WORDS TO MEMORY.
♪
( rings jingle )
NOW THEN, EUGEO AND KIRITO,
THE FATE OF THIS WORLD
IS UP TO YOU,
WHETHER IT IS
ENGULFED IN HELLFIRE
OR VANISHES ENTIRELY.
OR, WITH ANY LUCK, PERHAPS
YOU’LL FIND A THIRD PATH.
REGARDLESS, I HAVE TOLD YOU
ALL THAT I CAN TELL
AND GIVEN YOU
ALL THAT I CAN GIVE.
ALL THAT IS LEFT
IS TO TRUST IN YOURSELVES.
Eugeo: THANK YOU
FOR ALL YOUR HELP, CARDINAL.
I KNOW I’LL MAKE IT
TO THE TOP OF THE CATHEDRAL
AND RESTORE ALICE’S MEMORY.
( Kirito sighs )
( singing in Japanese )
Cardinal: EH...
( chuckles )
NOW THEN...
OFF WITH YOU!
( Kirito grunts )
( Cardinal chuckles )
Singer: ♪ THE IRIS TO YOU ♪